ROY FLORES

NEW YORK, NY | (917) 280-1448 | ROYFLORESNYC@GMAIL.COM <u>Github</u>: royFloresNyc | <u>Medium</u>: royfloresnyc | <u>LinkedIn</u>

SUMMARY

Full stack web and mobile app developer with experience in Ruby and JavaScript libraries and frameworks. Over a decade of experience as a professional theater performer. Innately curious with the ability to learn quickly. Adaptable, resilient, and collaborative. Fluent in English, Tagalog, and Abaknon; and a little bit of Spanish.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, Ruby, HTML5, CSS, React, Redux, NodeJS, Express, Ruby on Rails, React Native, Expo, SQL, PostgreSQL

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Roamr - Github: (Frontend, Backend) | Demo

A travel app that allows users to query any city, view photos, information, safety ratings, points of interest, and maps.

- Developed user interface with React Native, and architected a backend server using Ruby on Rails.
- Implemented user authorization and authentication using BCrypt and JWT.
- Leveraged third party APIs to render dynamic information about gueried cities.
- Utilized a third party Translator API to implement a language translator functionality.

Iron Budget - Github: (Frontend, Backend) | Demo

A financial accounting tool that allows users to keep track of their income and expenditures and analyze their spending habits.

- Implemented user interface employing React, and designed a RESTful API using Ruby on Rails.
- Created dynamic forms to allow users to enter, edit, and/or delete transactions.
- Leveraged a third party API to render locations of banks, ATM's, and other financial institutions near the user.
- Implemented dynamic charts to allow for visualization of users' financial habits.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Actor's Equity Association, Various Locations — *Actor / Performer* 2008 - 2020

- Studied scripts, music, and choreography, to successfully tell stories that capture audiences in theaters all across the country.
- Collaborated with directors, producers, writing staff and performance teams to determine optimal performance strategies and perfect approaches.
- Perfected acting, singing, dancing, and musical instrument skills through private pursuits, lessons and group activities while performing in shows or attending up to 5 auditions each week.

Great Performances, New York, NY - Captain (Service Manager)

2009 - 2019

- Met with clients, party planners, and service teams to discuss service needs and develop effective and practical solutions.
- Maintained team productivity and quality of service by establishing and maintaining clear benchmarks.
- Protected business, team members and customers by monitoring alcohol consumption and keeping operation in line with legal service requirements.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School — Full Stack Web Development

AUGUST 2020 - NOVEMBER 2020, NEW YORK, NY

American Musical and Dramatic Academy – Musical Theatre Performance

OCTOBER 2006 - FEBRUARY 2008, NEW YORK, NY

Southwestern College — completed 59 credits towards an Associate in Arts (AA) in Accounting (GPA: 3.88)
AUGUST 2004 - MAY 2006, CHULA VISTA, CA